A Finding Aid to the Hugo Gellert Papers, 1916-1986, in the Archives of American Art AAA.gellhugo
Archives of American Art
- Artwork, 1927-1981; Series 7; (Box 7, OV 10; 0.4 linear feet)
  Artwork that is part of identifiable, titled projects is filed first, including sketches for Gellert's 1934 book Karl Marx's Capital in Lithographs, and a set of silkscreen prints that he issued as a portfolio entitled Century of the Common Man in 1943. General files for sketches, sketchbooks, layouts, and prints filed after them. Sketches, drawings, and designs include a wide variety of material, from loose sketches and doodles to finished drawings, as well as text design, technical drawings, and floor plans. Notes and writings are common among the sketches and sketchbooks, and the sketchbook dated 1950 also contains a handwritten, autobiographical essay.
  Layouts and prints production elements include sketches, prints, typography, brownprints, photostats, and prints in various states.
  - "American Student Delegation to Russia," Silkscreen Poster, 1927; (See OV 10) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Karl Marx??s Capital in Lithographs, Sketches, circa 1933-1934; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
  - Unidentified Portrait, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Century of the Common Man, Silkscreen Prints, circa 1943; (See also OV 10) (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Monoprints, undated; (partially scanned) (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Sketches, Drawings, and Designs, circa 1939-1981; (4 folders; see also OV 10) (Box 7, Folder 13-16)
  - Sketchbooks, 1950, undated; (3 volumes in 2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 17-18)
  - Layouts and Print Production Elements, circa 1940-1954; (2 folders; see also OV 10) (Box 7, Folder 19-20)
  - Artwork by Others (Box 7)
    - "Stones" by Philip Reisman, circa 1933 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - "1514," Woodcuts by Gyula Derkovits, circa 1928-1929 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - "Sword into Plowshare," Woodcut by Anton Refregier, circa 1933 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Unsigned Prints, 1937, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
      (The first print is by Charles White, the last print is by Alexander Stavenitz)
  - Oversized Artwork (See box 7, f7, 10-11, 16, and 19) (Box 10 (OV))